(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
皆様、大変長らくお待たせいたしました。
Everyone, thank you so much for waiting.
かなたん爆誕！
Kanatan's explosive birth!
これから始まって参ります！
It's about to begin!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
コメントありがとうね！
Thanks for the comments!
そらもありがとう！
Sora, thank you too!
本当にお待たせいたしました。
Truly, thank you for waiting.
えー、みんなの応援のおかげで、
Um, thanks to everyone's support,
本当にみんなの応援のおかげで、
truly thanks to everyone's support,
こうしてね、大きな爆誕祭を開くことができて、
I'm able to hold such a big "Bakutansai" like this,
とっても嬉しいです。
and I'm very happy.
普段ホロライブを応援しているみんなに、
To everyone who always supports Hololive,
少しでも恩返しができるように、
so that I can give back even a little,
今日は一生懸命頑張りたいと思っております。
I want to work my hardest today.
それではみんな！
Now then, everyone!
タグ「#かなたん爆誕」でいっぱい呟いてね！
Please tweet a lot using the tag "#かなたん爆誕"!
始まるよ！かなたん爆誕！！
Here we go! Kanatan's explosive birth!!
せーの！
One, two!
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's not good enough
もうそんなんじゃほら
See, like that
心は進化するよ
My heart will evolve
もっともっと
More and more
恋愛サーキュレーション
Ren'ai Circulation
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If our relationship would disappear once put into words
言葉を消せばいいやって思ってた
Then I thought I should just get rid of words
恐れてた
I was afraid
だけどあれ？
But wait?
なんか違うかも…
Maybe that's not right...
千里の道も一歩から！
A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step!
石のように硬いそんな意志で
With a will as hard as a rock
ちりも積もれば大和撫子？
If dust piles up, it becomes a Yamato Nadeshiko?
「し」抜きで　いや「死ぬ気で！」
Without the "will," no, "with my life!"
ふわふわり　ふわふわる
Fluffy, fluff-fluff
あなたが名前を呼ぶ
Just you calling my name
それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Makes me float into space
ふわふわる　ふわふわり
Fluff-fluff, fluffy
あなたが笑っている
Just you smiling
それだけで笑顔になる
Makes me smile
神様ありがとう　運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate
めぐり逢えたことが　幸せなの
Being able to meet you is my happiness
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's not good enough
もうそんなんじゃほら
See, like that
心は進化するよ
My heart will evolve
もっともっと
More and more
もうそんなんじゃやだ
Yeah, I don't want it like that
ねぇそんなんじゃまだ
Hey, it's not enough yet
私のこと見ててね
Keep looking at me
ずっとずっと
Forever and ever
今日はかなたんのお誕生日！！
Today is Kanatan's birthday!!
イエーイ！おめでとう！
Yay! Happy Birthday!
かなたん爆誕しましたー！！
Kanatan has been explosively born!!
イエーイ！！
Yay!!
私の中のあなたほど
I know that my existence within you
あなたの中の私の存在は
isn't quite as large as
まだまだ大きくないことも
your existence within me yet,
わかってるけれど
but...
今この同じ瞬間
This same moment right now
共有してる時間
The time we're sharing
ちりも積もれば大和撫子！
Even dust piles up to become a Yamato Nadeshiko!
略して　ちりつもやまとなでこ！
In short, Chiri-Tsumo Yamato Nadeko!
クラクラり　クラクラる
Dizzy-dizzy, dizzy-diz
あなたを見上げたら
Just looking up at you
それだけで眩しすぎて
Is far too dazzling
クラクラる　クラクラり
Dizzy-diz, dizzy-dizzy
あなたを想っている
Just thinking about you
それだけで溶けてしまう
Makes me melt away
神様ありがとう　運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate
めぐり逢えたことが　幸せなの
Being able to meet you is my happiness
コ・イ・ス・ル　キ・セ・ツ・ハ
The sea-son-of-be-ing-in-love
ヨ・ク・バ・リ　サーキュレーション
is a gree-dy cir-cu-la-tion
コ・イ・ス・ル　キ・モ・チ・ハ
The feel-ing-of-be-ing-in-love
ヨ・ク・バ・リ　サーキュレーション
is a gree-dy cir-cu-la-tion
コ・イ・ス・ル　キ・ボ・ウ・ハ
The hope-of-be-ing-in-love
恋愛サーキュレーション
Renai Circulation
恋する乙女は欲張りサーキュレーション
Love-struck girls are a greedy circulation
ふわふわり ふわふわる あなたが名前を呼ぶ
Softly floating, softly flying, you call my name
それだけで宙へ浮ぶ
Just that makes me float into the air
ふわふわる ふわふわり あなたが笑っている
Softly flying, softly floating, you are laughing
それだけで笑顔になる
Just that makes me smile
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you God, even if it's a trick of fate
めぐり逢えたことが幸せなの
I'm happy that we could meet
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you God, even if it's a trick of fate
めぐり逢えたことが幸せなの
I'm happy that we could meet
でも そんなんじゃダメ
But that's no good
もう そんなんじゃほら
Look, like that
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart will evolve, more and more
もう そんなんじゃやだ
I don't like it like that
ねえ そんなんじゃまだ
Hey, not like that yet
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Keep looking at me, forever and ever
スイートマジック
Sweet Magic
イェーイ！
Yay!
はあちゃまだよー！
It's Haachama!
かなたんだよー！
It's Kanatan!
はあちゃまがゲストに来てくれましたー！
Haachama came as a guest!
はあちゃまっちゃまー！
Haachamachama~!
それさっき考えたやつねｗ
You just thought of that, didn't you? lol
イェーイ！
Yay!
甘くてハバネロなコトバ
Sweet and Habanero-like words
隠し味なににしよう?
What should the secret ingredient be?
純粋なオトメゴコロ
A pure girl's heart
甘い恋も絡めなくちゃ
Must involve a sweet love too
切なさ重ねてミルフィーユ
Layering sadness like a mille-feuille
酸味も仕上げにタルト
With some sourness for the tart finish
苦味も溶かしたケーキ
A cake with bitterness melted in
魔法をかけたら甘いキセキ
Cast a spell for a sweet miracle
甘さを抑えてみたとか
Saying I tried to hold back the sweetness
ミルク多めのコーヒーとか
Or like a coffee with lots of milk
その言い訳じゃ大人になれないの
With those excuses, I can't become an adult
そんなの絶対に絶対にやだやだやだ！
I absolutely, absolutely hate that!
ねぇあげようか 甘い罠
Hey, shall I give you a sweet trap?
ほら虜にしてあげる
See, I'll make you mine
そんな魔法 駆けぬけたら
If you run through such magic,
ちょっとだけ待たせてあげるわ
I'll make you wait just a little while
イェーイ！
Yay!
かなたんのケツぺんぺん！
Spanking Kanatan's butt!
ちょっ、待って、マジで疲れてるからｗ
Wait, hold on, I'm really tired! lol
かなたんのケツぺんぺん！
Spanking Kanatan's butt!
何？ うどん粉のしっぽ？
What? A tail made of flour?
何しようとしてんの！？ はあちゃまのしっぽ、わたあめ美味しそうｗ
What are you trying to do?! Haachama's tail, the cotton candy looks delicious! lol
それ予備機だしｗ
That's a spare one! lol
えっ、おかしだろｗ ふざけた一人だけ！
Eh, that's weird! lol Only one person playing around!
あ, 待って, それで料理作ろうとしてますｗ
Ah, wait, she's trying to cook with that! lol
やめてくださいよ！ はあちゃまのしっぽ！
Please stop! Haachama's tail!
はあちゃま先輩！
Haachama-senpai!
たったひと口が足りなくて
Just one bite wasn't enough
赤いイチゴ味はじまって
The red strawberry flavor begins
その一口の魔法で見せないわ
I won't show you the magic of that one bite
完璧に作るわ ひとりでもでもでも
I'll make it perfectly, even all by myself
ねぇ気付いてんでしょ? わかってんでしょ?
Hey, you noticed, right? You understand, right?
隠し味の恋ゴコロ
The secret ingredient is love
苦味とか 酸味とか
Bitterness and sourness,
そういうのもたまにはいいわ
Things like that are fine once in a while
意地っぱりで わがままな
Stubborn and selfish,
そんな甘い魔法使い
Such a sweet magician
はあちゃま来てくれてありがとうー！
Haachama, thank you for coming!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
誕生日プレゼント何くれるの？
What are you giving me for my birthday?
誕生日プレゼントはケーキだよ！ はい、どうぞー！
Your birthday present is a cake! Here you go!
さっきの材料のケーキ！？ 何？ 食べてね？ 味見してみる？
A cake made from those ingredients just now?! What? Eat it? You want to try a taste?
いやいやいや、いいわいいわｗ はいどうぞー、ほら、マジで
No no no, I'm good! lol Here, go ahead, look, seriously!
やだやだ！
No way, no way!
美味しいもの食べさせてよ！
Let me eat something delicious!
やだやだ～！
No, no~!
早く早く！
Hurry, hurry!
正しさとは 愚かさとは
What is right? What is foolish?
それが何か見せつけてやる
I'll show you what they are.
うっせぇわ
Shut up!
うっせぇわ / 作詞・作曲：syudou
Usseewa / Lyrics & Composition: syudou
ちっちゃな頃から優等生
I've been a model student since I was small.
気づいたら大人になっていた
Before I knew it, I had become an adult.
ナイフのような思考回路
Without any such thing as...
持ち合わせる訳もなく
...a knife-like thought process.
でも遊び足りない 何か足りない
But I haven't played enough. Something's missing.
困っちまうこれは誰かのせい
It's troubling, and it's someone's fault.
あてもなくただ混乱するエイデイ
Aimlessly just confusing every day.
それもそうか
I guess that's right.
最新の流行は当然の把握
Naturally grasping the latest trends.
経済の動向も通勤時チェック
Checking economic trends during my commute too.
純情な精神で入社しワーク
Entering a company with a pure heart and working.
そんじゃそこらのルールです
Those are just the rules around here.
はぁー？
Huh?
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
あなたが思うより健康です
I'm healthier than you think.
一切合切凡庸な
A completely mediocre person...
あなたじゃ分からないかもね
...like you probably wouldn't understand.
嗚呼よく似合う
Ah, it suits you well.
その可もなく不可もないメロディ
That melody that's neither good nor bad.
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
頭の出来が違うので問題はナシ
My brain's built differently, so no problem.
つっても私も半人間
That said, I'm also half-human.
殴ったりするのはナンセンス
Hitting and such is nonsense.
だったら言葉の銃口を
In that case, if I press...
その頭に突きつけて撃てば
...the muzzle of words against that head and fire...
マジやばない？ 止まれやしない
Isn't it crazy? Can't stop.
不平不満だらけの成れの果て
The result of being full of complaints.
サディスティックに変貌する精神
A spirit that transforms sadistically.
クソだりぃな
It's so damn tiresome.
酒が空いたグラスあればすぐに注ぎなさい
If there's an empty glass of alcohol, pour it immediately.
皆が摘みやすいように串外しなさい
Remove the skewers so everyone can pick them up easily.
会計や注文は先陣を切る
Being the first to pay or order.
不文律なマナーです
These are unwritten rules of etiquette.
はぁー？
Huh?
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
ッセ口塞げ限界です
Shut your mouth, I'm at my limit.
絶対絶対現代の
Without a doubt, I'm the...
代弁者は私やろがい
spokesperson for the modern age!
もう見飽きたわ
I'm tired of seeing it.
二番煎じ言い換えのパロディ
The second-hand reworded parody.
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
丸々と肉付いたその顔面にバツ
An 'X' on that face plump with meat.
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ...
Shut up, shut up, shut up...
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
私が俗に言う天才です
I'm what they commonly call a genius.
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
あなたが思うより健康です
I'm healthier than you think.
一切合切凡庸な
A completely mediocre person...
あなたじゃ分からないかもね
...like you probably wouldn't understand.
嗚呼つまらねぇ
Ah, how boring.
何回聞かせるんだそのメモリ
How many times are you going to play that memory?
うっせぇうっせぇうっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
私も大概だけど
I'm pretty bad too, but...
どうだっていいぜ問題はナシ
...whatever, no problem.
LOSER
LOSER / 作詞・作曲：米津 玄師
LOSER / Lyrics & Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
いつもどおり 独り独り
As always, alone, alone.
ご馳走様 こんな日々もはや懲り懲り
'Thank you for the meal.' I'm already fed up with these days.
もうどこにも行きやしないのに
Even though I won't go anywhere...
夢見て おやすみ
...I dream and say goodnight.
いっそ僕らこのふうに
Might as well, we, like this...
僕らの夜に飽き飽き
...bored with our night.
また踊り踊り出す明日に
Before getting disgusted by tomorrow...
嫌気さす前にさよなら
...which starts to dance again, goodbye.
去らば掲げろ 旗を 止まない祝砲のなかで
So long, raise your flag amidst the endless celebration
四半世紀の結果出来た 青い顔のスパスタが お腹空かしては待ってる
A pale-faced superstar, the product of a quarter-century, is waiting, hungry
アイマイナー どうせだったら 遠吠えだっていいだろう
I'm a minor; if anything, a howl would be fine
もう一回 もう一回行こうぜ 僕らの声
One more time, let's go one more time, with our voices
アイマイナー ずっと前から 聞こえていた
I'm a minor, I've heard it for a long time
いつか ポケットに隠した 声が
The voice I hid in my pocket one day
ああだこうだの嫉妬なんか 最低の空は悪天候
All this jealous chatter, the lowest sky is bad weather
ほら 窓から覗いて待ってんのさ 八丁畷のよう
Look, I'm waiting, peeking out the window like Haccho-nawate
夜も蚊とも昔の人よ 中指立ててもしょうがないの
The night, the mosquitoes, the people of the past; there's no use flipping them off
今 立ち上がるための お勉強 朗らかな表情
I'm studying to stand up now, with a cheerful expression
ブルーフルに見るアホに 放たれるそれを端から笑えよ
Laugh at those fools who see everything in blue
巨大な知識を抱え込んでは 悶々 すり減った残るスペア不動
Hugging a mountain of knowledge, agonizing, the remaining spare path is worn down
膝抱えても何も出ねえ ほら 長い前髪で前が見えねえ
Nothing comes from hugging your knees; see, I can't see forward with this long fringe
笑っちまうね パッと沸き立って フワッと消えちゃえる こんな輪廻
It's laughable, boiling up and vanishing in a puff, this cycle of rebirth
愛されたいなら そう言おうぜ
If you want to be loved, let's say so
待ってるだけじゃ 伝わらないね
Just waiting won't get the message across
永遠の宿場も そっぽ向いて
Even the eternal post town turns its back
天国は遠く 向こうの方へ
And heaven goes far, far away
耳を澄ませとくぜ今 響き出した音が鳴らすな
I'll keep my ears open now; don't stop the sound that's started to echo
呼吸を整えて
Steady your breathing
いつか出会えるはずの 黄金の色したアイライトを
The golden-colored eye-light you're bound to meet someday
きっと掴んで放すな
Be sure to grab it and don't let go
アイマイナー 名前もないなら どうなったっていいだろう
I'm a minor; if I don't even have a name, what does it matter?
だらしない 砂嵐に混じり ハイさようなら
Slovenly, mixed in with the sandstorm, well, goodbye
アイマイナー 期待したいぜ 願うまま
I'm a minor, I want to have hope, just as I wish
進め ロスタイムのその また奥へ行け
Go on, go even further into the depths of that loss time
愛されたいなら そう言おうぜ
If you want to be loved, let's say so
待ってるだけじゃ 足りないね
Just waiting isn't enough
永遠の宿場も そっぽ向いて
Even the eternal post town turns its back
天国は遠く 向こうの方へ
And heaven goes far, far away
ここらで一つ 踊ってみようぜ
Let's try dancing a bit here
夜が明けるまで 転がっていこうぜ
Let's keep rolling until dawn
聞こえてんなら 声出していこうぜ
If you can hear me, let's raise our voices
アイマイナー どうせだったら 遠吠えだっていいだろう
I'm a minor; if anything, a howl would be fine
もう一回 もう一回行こうぜ 僕らの声
One more time, let's go one more time, with our voices
アイマイナー ずっと前から 聞こえていた
I'm a minor, I've heard it for a long time
いつか ポケットに隠した 声が
The voice I hid in my pocket one day
ここらで一つ 踊ってみようぜ
Let's try dancing a bit here
夜更けまで 転がっていこうぜ
Let's keep rolling until late at night
聞こえてんなら 声出していこうぜ
If you can hear me, let's raise our voices
はい！イェーイ！
Yes! Yay!
ねねちゃーん！ありがとうー！
Nene-chan! Thank you!
ということでね、えー、ちょっと待って息が...
And so, uh, wait a second, I'm out of breath...
ねねちゃんがね、来てくださいました！
Nene-chan has come to join us!
こんばんはー。いやちょっと、ねー。
Good evening! Wow, that was something.
ねぇ！
Right!
できたてホヤホヤの、もう...
Fresh off the press, just...
ねねちゃんにはね、本当にね、あの、ぜひね一緒に歌いたいという話をしていまして。
I've really been talking with Nene-chan about how I definitely wanted to sing with her.
そして3Dのお披露目が、あるとその時にね。3月の終わりぐらいだったっけ？オファーしたの。
And when I heard there was a 3D debut... Was it around the end of March when I reached out?
そう！
Yes!
教えてくれたんで、もうそれは絶対に出てほしいねって話をしたんだよね。
Since you told me that, I said I definitely wanted you to appear.
そう。
Right.
嬉しかったー。
I was so happy!
これからは一杯こうやってライブに出たりとか、一緒に3Dで遊んだりとかしようね。
From now on, let's appear in many lives like this and play in 3D together.
しようね！
Let's do it!
イェーイ！ずっと待っててよー！やったやったー！
Yay! I've been waiting forever! We did it, we did it!
もうねねちゃん凄そう。歌上手いじゃん。
Nene-chan, you're amazing. You're so good at singing.
え、人一倍ね、ね。
Eh, more than most, right?
息一つ上がってないやん。僕...
You're not even out of breath. I'm...
ガチバチに疲れてるな。
Totally, utterly exhausted.
ガチバチ。やべえ全出ししちゃったんですけど。
Totally. Man, I gave it my all.
めっちゃ余裕じゃん、ちょっと。イェーイイェーイ。
You seem so relaxed! Yay, yay!
あ、いいねいいね。ちょっとねねちゃんせっかくだからね、もっと見たいよね。
Ah, nice, nice. Since Nene-chan is here, we want to see more, right?
二人で見たいよね。二人でいるとこ見たいんだよ、ファンもね。
We want to see the two of you together. The fans want to see you together too.
せーの。ピスピスピス。
One, two... Peace, peace, peace!
イェーイ！
Yay!
嬉しい、本当に、本当に。もう。
I'm so happy, really, truly.
本当今日おめでとうございます。
Happy birthday today, seriously.
ありがとうございます！ねねちゃん。
Thank you! Nene-chan.
お誕生日が、主役だからね本日は。
Since the birthday girl is the star today.
本日の主役です！
I'm today's star!
あー嬉しいね。またこれからも一杯歌ったりとか、コラボもね。
Ah, I'm so glad. Let's keep singing together and doing collabs.
やろう！やろうぜ！いっぱい歌おう！
Let's do it! Let's do it! Let's sing a lot!
いっぱい歌おうぜ、スーパーねねち！
Let's sing a lot, Super Nenechi!
イェーイ！
Yay!
という感じで、はい。
Something like that, yes.
ねね、歌って…歌ったのは「Loser」でございますが。
Nene, the song we... the one we sang was 'Loser'.
かっこいい曲だったけど、今度はね、ちょっと電波な曲とかも僕はねねちゃんと歌ってみたいので。
It was a cool song, but next time, I want to try singing a 'denpa' style song with Nene-chan.
えー、やろやろ！
Eh, let's do it!
やってみましょう！お願いします。
Let's do it! Please.
イェーイ、イェーイ、イェーイ。
Yay, yay, yay.
という感じで、はい。
Something like that, yes.
それではですね、お次の曲の準備いたしましょうか。
Well then, shall we prepare for the next song?
はい！
Yes!
さて、それでは。
Well then.
次の曲は、せーの！
The next song is... one, two!
「世界五分前仮説」！
"World Five Minutes Ago Theory"!
世界五分前仮説
作詞・作曲：sasakure.UK
World Five Minutes Ago Theory
Lyrics & Composition: sasakure.UK
相対性存在論
Relativity Ontology
抽象的スレッショルド
Abstract Threshold
隔絶されていく
Being isolated
クリグロン空虚
Krygron Emptiness
等倍成長現実
1:1 Growth Reality
改竄性センドイド
Falsifiable Sendoid
拡散されていく
Being diffused
無味無臭無情
Tasteless, odorless, heartless
ライヤーの少年は
The liar boy
信者を垣間見
Glimpsed the believers
小さく笑う
Giggled softly
「世界に意味はない」と
"There is no meaning to the world"
ディスプレイのガズバ
Gazba on the display
ボ・ボ・ボ・ボ・ロン
Bo-bo-bo-bo-ron
曖昧化した
Blurred
愛とアイの境界
The boundary between love and self
存在論
Ontology
例えば世界が今
For example, if the world now
五分前の策ですら
Even the schemes from five minutes ago
否定している
Is denying
としたら？
If that were the case?
相対性
Relativity
再構成
Reconstruction
嘘だ、誰もが皆
It's a lie, everyone
その証明など、できないから
Because they cannot prove it
さぁ、僕ら刹那
Come, we are a moment
世界を奏でていこう
Let's keep playing the world
みんなー！
Everyone!
次はAZKiさんが来てくれましたー！
Next, AZKi-san has come to join us!
やったー！よろしくねー！
Yay! Nice to meet you!
イェーイ、イェーイ、イェーイ！
Yay, yay, yay!
ということで！
And so!
今日もみんな、ハッシュタグで呟いてくれてるかな？
I wonder if everyone is tweeting with the hashtag today too?
かなたん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Kanatan, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
「#かなたん爆誕」でいっぱい呟いてねー！
Tweet a lot with "#かなたん爆誕"!
呟いてねー！
Tweet a lot!
ようこそ、僕たちの
Welcome to our
喪失した世界へ
Lost world
さて、君は何を思い叫んだ？
Well, what did you think and scream?
老婆は戦慄を
The old woman, a shudder
信者は真実を
The believer, the truth
少年は世界を
The boy, the world
みんな、まだまだ盛り上がれるかー！？
Everyone, can you still get hyped up?!
声出していくぞー！
Let's hear your voices!
あぁ、例えば世界が今
Ah, for example, if the world now
五分前の世界すら
Even the world from five minutes ago
拒絶している
Is rejecting
としたら？
If that were the case?
相対性
Relativity
再構成
Reconstruction
空想、でもよかった
A fantasy, but it was fine
等身大の音の波
A life-sized wave of sound
あぁ、五分間の
Ah, for five minutes
優しい世界を探した
I searched for a gentle world
空想、誰もが皆
Fantasy, everyone
その肯定すら、できないのさ
Can't even affirm it
さぁ、僕ら刹那
Come, we are a moment
形ある歌を歌う
Singing a song with form
打上花火
作詞・作曲：米津 玄師
Uchiage Hanabi
Lyrics & Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
あの日見渡した渚を
The shore we looked out upon that day...
今も思い出すんだ
...I still remember it now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words carved in the sand...
君の後ろ姿
...the sight of your back.
寄り返す波が
The returning waves...
足元をよぎり何かをさらう
...brush past my feet and sweep something away.
夕凪の中
In the evening calm...
日暮れだけが通り過ぎてゆく
...only the twilight passes by.
パッと光って咲いた
Suddenly lit up and bloomed...
花火を見ていた
...we watched the fireworks.
きっとまだ
Surely still...
終わらない夏が
...the summer hasn't ended yet.
曖昧な心を
Our ambiguous hearts...
解かして繋いだ
...thawed and connected.
この夜が
I wanted this night...
続いて欲しかった
...to continue.
あと何度君と同じ花火を見られるかなって
I wonder how many more times I can see the fireworks with you
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
What can I do for that smiling face?
傷つくこと　喜ぶこと　繰り返す波と情動
Getting hurt, being happy, the repeating waves and emotions
最終列車の音
The sound of the last train
何度でも　言葉にして君を呼ぶよ
I'll call out to you as many times as it takes
波を選び　もう一度
Choosing a wave, once more
もう二度と　悲しまずに済むように
So that we never have to be sad again
ハッと息を飲めば　消えちゃいそうな光が
With a sudden gasp, a light that seems like it might vanish...
きっとまだ　胸に住んでいた
...was surely still living in my heart.
手を伸ばせば触れた　温かい未来は
The warm future I could touch if I reached out...
密かに二人を見守っていた
...was secretly watching over the two of us.
パッと花火が
Suddenly, the fireworks...
夜に咲いた
...bloomed in the night.
静かに消えた
Quietly disappeared.
離さないで
Don't let go.
もう少しだけ
Just a little longer.
このままで
Just like this.
あの日見渡した渚を
The shore we looked out upon that day...
今も思い出すんだ
...I still remember it now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words carved in the sand...
君の後ろ姿
...the sight of your back.
パッと光って咲いた
Suddenly lit up and bloomed...
花火を見ていた
...we watched the fireworks.
きっとまだ
Surely still...
終わらない夏が
...the summer hasn't ended yet.
曖昧な心を
Our ambiguous hearts...
解かして繋いだ
...thawed and connected.
この夜が
I wanted this night...
続いて欲しかった
...to continue.
それでは、打ち上げ花火、
And now, 'Uchiage Hanabi',
天音かなたと宝鐘マリンで歌わせていただきます。
performed by Amane Kanata and Houshou Marine. Please enjoy!
イェーイ！
Yay!
あー見てかなた！すごい花火！
Ah, look Kanata! Amazing fireworks!
きれいだね。
They're pretty.
They're beautiful.
なあかなた、打ち上げ花火、
Hey Kanata, fireworks...
上から見る？下から見る？
...view from the top? View from the bottom?
一人で見る？
View alone?
んー、ちょっと...
Hmm... just a bit...
真面目に考えてんじゃねーよ！
Don't take it so seriously!
かなた！かなた！かなた！かなた！
Kanata! Kanata! Kanata! Kanata!
I'm a dreamer　ひそむパワー
I'm a dreamer, a hidden power
私の世界
My world
夢と恋と不安でできてる
Is made of dreams, love, and anxiety
でも想像もしないもの　隠れてるはず
But things I can't even imagine should be hidden
空に向かう木々のように
Like trees reaching for the sky
あなたをまっすぐ見つめてる
I'm looking straight at you
見つけたいな
I want to find it
叶えたいな
I want to make it come true
信じるそれだけで　越えられないものはない
There's nothing that can't be overcome just by believing
歌うように
Like singing
奇跡のように
Like a miracle
想いがすべてを　変えてゆくよ
My feelings will change everything
きっと
Surely
驚くくらい
Surprising as it may be
みんな！百鬼あやめ先輩が来てくれましたー！
Everyone! Nakiri Ayame-senpai has come!
みんなありがとー！かなたんおめでとー！
Thank you everyone! Happy birthday, Kanatan!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
I'm a dreamer
ひそむパワー
A hidden power
まだ見ぬ世界
A world not yet seen
そこで何が待っていても
No matter what is waiting there
もし理想と違っても
Even if it's different from my ideals
恐れはしない
I won't be afraid
鳥たちは風に乗り　旅をしてゆく
Birds ride the wind and go on a journey
今日から明日へと
From today to tomorrow
伝えたいな
I want to tell you
叫びたいな
I want to shout it
この世に一つだけの　存在である私
I am the only existence of its kind in this world
祈るように
Like praying
星のように
Like a star
小さな光だけど　いつかはずっと
A small light, but someday it will be...
もっと
More
強くなりたい
I want to become stronger
限界のない可能性がここにある
The limitless possibilities are here,
この手に
In these hands
It's all beyond
見つけたいな
I want to find it
叶えたいな
I want to make it come true
信じるそれだけで　越えられないものはない
There's nothing that can't be overcome just by believing
歌うように
Like singing
奇跡のように
Like a miracle
想いがすべてを　変えてゆくよ
My feelings will change everything
きっと
Surely
驚くくらい
Surprising as it may be
プラチナ
Platinum
イェーイ！
Yay!
みんなありがとー！
Thank you, everyone!
はい！ということで、みんな、お待たせかな？
Yes! So, everyone, did I keep you waiting?
ここまで...
Up until now...
ちょっと待って。うん。ここまで、えー、お送りさせていただきました、かなたん爆誕。
Wait a moment. Yes. Up until now, we've presented Kanatan's Birthday Bash.
ホロメンのみんなに本当に本当にいっぱい協力していただいて、今日ね、迎えることができました。
With so much help from all the Hololive members, I was able to reach today.
もう本当にみんなありがとう。
Thank you so much, everyone.
僕がね、あの、みんなの力をこんなに借りていいのかなと、
I was thinking if it was really okay for me to borrow everyone's power like this,
えー、すごく、あの、リハの時とかもね、思っていたんですが、
even back during rehearsals,
ホロライブという、ね、ところに僕もとっても、あの、本当にいろんなことをね、いろんなものをいただいているので、
but since I've received so much from being here in Hololive,
ちょっとでもね、ホロライブ好きなみんなが楽しいなと思えるような、そんなライブになってたら嬉しいなと思います！
I'd be happy if this live show made everyone who likes Hololive have a good time!
てな感じで、このあたりで、ななななんと！おしらせがいくつもございます！
And with that, right now, I have several announcements!
まずはこちら！
First is this!
デデン！えー、恒例の誕生日記念のグッズが出ます。ボイスもね、一緒に出ます。
Ta-da! My usual birthday commemorative goods are coming out. The voice packs are also coming out.
今回はね、おしおママに描き下ろして、今回も、今回も描き下ろしてもらいました。
This time as well, Oshio-mama drew the illustrations for us.
見て！これ水族館で君とさ、ちょっとデートしているときのおめかしの僕なんだけど、どうかな？
Look! This is me dressed up for a date with you at an aquarium. What do you think?
えーとね、アクリルブロック、マグカップ、そして学生証！
Let's see, an acrylic block, a mug, and a student ID card!
ね、みんなさ、マグカップと学生証欲しいってさ、ね、言ってたでしょ？僕とさ、喋ってたじゃん。覚えてる？
You guys said you wanted a mug and a student ID, right? We talked about it. Remember?
あちらをね、今回はご用意させていただきました。
We've prepared those for you this time.
そしてね、あの、全部セット購入者特典というものには、直筆でメッセージもさせていただきます！
And as a bonus for buying the full set, I'll include a handwritten message!
え、もうね概要欄にね、グッズの...あ、こんな感じ、あ、こちら。アクリルブロックこんな感じなの。見て見て見て見て。可愛いでしょ？
The link is in the description... Ah, like this. The acrylic block looks like this. Look, look! Isn't it cute?
これね、結構大きめのサイズでございます。
This is quite a large size.
あ、トレンドも入ってた？タグの。タグのトレンドも入っておった？あった。みんな、みんな本当にありがとう。
Ah, did we trend? On Twitter? We did? Everyone, thank you so much.
そして学生証出るかな？学生証、マグカップ、あ、マグカップ、あ、学生証出た。
And will the student ID show up? Student ID, mug... Ah, the student ID is here.
見て！これ。ね。いいでしょ？生徒手帳風台紙で、これ。これぜひ手に入れてほしい。
Look at this! Isn't it nice? It's a student handbook-style mount. I really want you to get this.
そしてね、ちょっとここにさ、あ、上に書いてあるけど、学生証にはね、シリアルナンバーが入るので、世界で一つだけになっております。
And, as it says up there, the student IDs will have serial numbers, so each one is unique in the world.
みんな世界で一枚の学生証をね、ゲットしてほしいなと思います。
I hope everyone gets their own one-of-a-kind student ID.
マグカップも出るかな？ドドン！あ、こんな感じでね。ハッピーバースデー。ありがとう、本当に。
Will the mug show up too? Ta-da! Like this. Happy birthday. Thank you, truly.
てな感じで、えー、もうね概要欄にグッズの販売ページ載っていると思いますが、えーと10時かな？このあとすぐ22時に販売開始かな。購入ができると思います。
So, the sales page for the goods should be in the description, and starting at 10:00 PM tonight, they'll be available for purchase.
アクセスできると思いますので、みんなチェックしてみてね！
You should be able to access it then, so please check it out!
そしてそして！
And furthermore!
そしてそして、あ、こちら、あ、全部セット、あ、こちら。みんな見て。こっそりね、僕のあのサイン、ちょっとあの、こっそりさ、ちょっと変わったの。
And furthermore... Ah, the full set. Look, everyone. Secretly, my signature has changed slightly.
あのね、この猫ちゃんと、あの羽とかの位置がね、ちょっと逆になったりしたんです。
The positions of the cat and the wings have been swapped.
ね、見て可愛いでしょ？ぜひぜひ手に入れてね！ありがとう。
Look, isn't it cute? Please get it! Thank you.
そしてそしてそして！ドドン！
And and and! Ta-da!
ドドドドン！ジャーン！明日は同じ4期生のね、同期、桐生ココの新衣装のお披露目です！
Ta-da-da-da! Ta-da! Tomorrow is the reveal of my 4th generation genmate Kiryu Coco's new outfit!
明日の、えーと10時だったかな？22時ですね。にココが新衣装のお披露目をするので、みんなぜひ見てください！
At 10:00 PM tomorrow... yes, 22:00, Coco will reveal her new outfit, so please watch it!
え、このさ、ちょっとシルエットだとね、なんか、なんだろう。ツインテールみたいな感じだけど、服着てんのかって感じもね、
Judging by this silhouette, it looks like... twin-tails? But it also makes me wonder if she's even wearing clothes,
正直してるんですが、どんな感じになるかぜひ明日見てね！
to be honest. Please watch tomorrow to see what it's like!
そしてそのあとね、23時から明日は4期生のモンハンコラボがあります！
And after that, from 23:00 tomorrow, there's a 4th generation Monster Hunter collab!
僕はちょっと実況ということでね、4人のプレイを、もうね見たいなと。思っておりますので、そちらもチェックよろしくお願いします。
I'll be doing the commentary, and I'm looking forward to watching the four of them play. Please check that out too.
そしてそして！デデデデン！
And furthermore! Ta-da-da-da!
ドドン！とうとう来た！え、ドルオタ天使！もう明日、明日の12時半、お昼。お昼の12時半に開始いたします！
Ta-da! It's finally here! 'Dol-ota Tenshi'! Starting tomorrow at 12:30 PM.
毎週火水金のね、お昼から30分20分くらいの枠でホロライブの紹介番組をやりたいなと思っております。
I'm planning to do a Hololive introduction program every Tuesday, Wednesday, and Friday for about 20-30 minutes during lunch.
みんなね、ぜひぜひ遊びに来てください。ホロライブのことね、まだわかんないな、知らないなっていう方にもぜひぜひ知っていただきたいなというね、そんな感じで企画をやってまいります。
Everyone, please come and visit. I'm doing this project so that people who don't know much about Hololive can learn more about it.
イェーイ！ドドン！ありがとう。そして、え、もう一つ！デデデデデン、こちら！ドドン！ヒバナ！
Yay! Ta-da! Thank you. And one more thing! This! Ta-da! 'Hibana'!
このあと10時から、22時から...
Starting from 10:00 PM tonight, 22:00...
...からね、あのプレミア公開が始まりますのでぜひ見てください。よろしく！
...since the premiere reveal will start, so please check it out. Thank you!
そして最後に、ドドーン！すごいお知らせがあります！
And finally, ta-da! I have a huge announcement!
告知
Announcement
天音かなた オリジナル曲制作開始
Amane Kanata's original song production has begun
作曲は...
The composer is...
代表曲『シュガーソングとビターステップ』『Rising Hope』『オリオンをなぞる』
Hits: 'Sugar Song and Bitter Step', 'Rising Hope', 'Orion o Nazoru'
田淵智也さんに決定！！
It's decided: Tomoya Tabuchi!!
ダダダダーン！やっと発表できたー！
Ta-da! I finally got to announce it!
みんな！とうとうオリジナル曲をね、作っていただけることになりました！
Everyone! I'm finally going to have an original song made for me!
そしてみんなが知ってるあの田淵さん！マジで、マジだから、本当だからね！
And it's by the Tabuchi-san that everyone knows! Seriously, I'm serious, it's for real!
申し訳ないですね、あのオリジナル曲もね、だいぶもう進んでおりますので、ぜひ続報をお待ちください！
Sorry to keep you waiting, but the original song is already quite far along, so please wait for updates!
よろしくお願いします！ねえみんな、ちょっとマジでさ、
I'm counting on you! Hey everyone, seriously,
もしかしたらこの配信のね、この部分をさ、田淵さんがご覧になる可能性があるわけ。
there's a chance Tabuchi-san might see this part of the stream.
だからちょっと皆さん、「やべー田淵さんちょっとやば」っていうのをさ、ちょっと、
So everyone, please say 'Holy crap, Tabuchi-san is amazing' or something,
まあ言わなくても言ってるね、言ってる言ってる！もうこれ見られるから、みんなも見られるから田淵さんに。よろしくね！
Well, you're saying it anyway! He's going to see this, he'll see all of you. Be nice!
ってな感じで、えーっと、それではね、お知らせはこの様な感じでちょっとドドドーンと行きましたが、
So, with that... the announcements went by in a flash like that, but...
あとね、ま、シークレットゲストもまだね、登場していないし、ってな感じで、えー1曲多くソロで歌わせていただきたいと思います。
also, the secret guest hasn't appeared yet, so I'd like to sing one more song solo.
プレミア公開ね、この後する、「ヒバナ」。
The one that's getting a premiere reveal after this: 'Hibana'.
コンカツ優しくノックして　乗り込め　ココロの奪還戦
Gently knock on the soul, and board the ship for the battle to take back the heart
妄想ばかりがフラッシュして　加速するパルス　答えはどこだろう
Only delusions flash before me; as the pulse accelerates, where is the answer?
弱音はミュートして　くだらないことで躊躇して
Mute your weaknesses, hesitate over trivial things
冗談ばかりでアッハッハ　壊せない壁が　キスを迫るでしょう
Laughing at nothing but jokes; an unbreakable wall will surely demand a kiss
有り得ない　そんなわけないや
Impossible, there's no way that's true
有り得ない　勝ってくれるでしょう
Impossible, you'll win for me, won't you?
その頭を撃ち抜いて
Shoot through that head of yours
終わんない愛を抱いてたくないの　もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
I don't want to hold onto an endless love; make me more properly anxious
いないいないばぁで演じて欲しいの　もっとちゃんと応えてよ
I want you to perform like peek-a-boo; respond to me more properly
nanana... 未完成だって何度でも言うんだ
nanana... I'll say it again and again, even if it's incomplete
nanana... 脳から漏れた愛の中で
nanana... Inside the love that leaked from the brain
堂々これでアイコだって　止まらない時に困っちゃって
Magnificently, this makes us even; troubled by the time that won't stop
完全主義スマイルを君に　困惑する声に目眩　戸惑うな
Giving you a perfectionist smile; dizzy from the bewildered voices, don't be confused
Let me go, get the escape
If you stay, we'll desert officially
Now how long you fall for the old escape?
Better give up and show and defy your way!
有り得ない　こっちを選んで
Impossible, choose this way
有り得ない　こっちを壊して
Impossible, destroy this way
心の目を引き抜いて
Pull out the eyes of the heart
不甲斐ない愛を愛したくないの　もっとちゃんと隠してよ
I don't want to love a worthless love; hide it more properly
いないいない暗いを聞いて欲しいの　もっとちゃんと溶かしてよ
I want you to hear the 'peek-a-boo dark'; melt it more properly
nanana... 未完成だって何度でも言うんだ
nanana... I'll say it again and again, even if it's incomplete
nanana... 脳から漏れた愛の中で
nanana... Inside the love that leaked from the brain
有り得ない　そんなわけないや
Impossible, there's no way that's true
有り得ない　勝ってくれるでしょう
Impossible, you'll win for me, won't you?
その頭を撃ち抜いて
Shoot through that head of yours
撃ち抜いて
Shoot through it
終わんない愛を抱いてたくないの　もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
I don't want to hold onto an endless love; make me more properly anxious
いないいないばぁで演じて欲しいの　もっとちゃんと応えてよ
I want you to perform like peek-a-boo; respond to me more properly
nanana... 未完成だって何度でも言うんだ
nanana... I'll say it again and again, even if it's incomplete
nanana... 脳から漏れた愛の中で
nanana... Inside the love that leaked from the brain
ヒバナ
Hibana
脳内曝した愛の中で
Within this love exposed in my head
die die die die 愛してたいの
die die die die, I want to keep loving
もっとちゃんと痛くしてよ
Please make it hurt more, properly
醒めないくらいにきっと楽しいの
It must be fun enough that I won't wake up
もっとちゃんと溶かしてよ
Please melt me more, properly
未完成だって何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it over and over, even if it's incomplete
脳内曝した愛の中で
Within this love exposed in my head
未完成だって何度でも言うんだ
I'll say it over and over, even if it's incomplete
NO!
脳内曝した愛の中で
Within this love exposed in my head
かなたん爆誕
Kanatan's Birthday Bash